#### CV

## Sokolik Grigorii

#### 13 June 2021

#### About

I am a backend developer with more than 10 years of experience. Most of the time I more or less dealt with PHP. Last 5 years I actively use Go. I have accepted pull requests in PHP source and big opensource projects both on PHP and Go (like codeception, etcd etc.) and some contributions to Linux coreutils. Also I have a bit of experience of managing up to 5 members remote development team.

#### **Education**

2005-2010 - MSU, department of mechanics and mathematics

#### Experience

## September 2019 - Present - Samrtly.io (Software Engineer)

Technology & infrostructure stack

Golang, PHP, TypeScrypt, JavaScript, React, Angular, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Redis, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Development & management tools & services

Git, Github, Jenkins, Github Actions, Atlassian products, JetBrains products, JFrog products

## July 2019 - September 2019 - Kurshi Games (Backend advisor)

Technology & infrostructure stack

GCP, GCE, GKE, Golang, PHP, Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Kafka, Vertica, Appache Airflow Development & management tools & services

Git, Gitlab, Google Cloud Builds, Vim

# February 2019 - May 2019 - Acronis (Senior developer)

Technology & infrostructure stack

Linux, OpenVZ, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Percona, RabbitMQ, Golang, Python, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Jenkins, PyPi, Git, Vim, Atlassian products, JetBrains products

# October 2017 - January 2019 - AVITO (Senior developer)

Goals & achievements

- create fast, scalable and flexible analytic tool for professional users (very similar to google analytics)
- increase stability of several applications
- begin to lead team (solve internal problems, watch out for motivation etc...)

#### Technology & infrostructure stack

Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, Vertica, ClickHouse, MongoDB, Reddis, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Golang, PHP7, PHP-FPM, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Composer, Git, Vim, Atlassian products, JetBrains products

## May 2016 - October 2017 - Ronte Limited (Team lead)

#### Goals & achievements

- create project's core architecture (secure chat + p2p calls)
- manage tasks for my programmers
- review code
- manage continuous integration tools
- deploy

#### Technology & infrostructure stack

Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, MongoDB, ZeroMQ, Reddis, Golang, PHP7, PHP-FPM, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Jira, Jenkins, Composer, Git, Bitbucket, Vim

## August 2015 - May 2016 - Delivery club LLC (Senior developer, mobile API expert)

#### Goals & achievements

- refactor ugly cms-like code, implement basic MVC patterns
- develop and integrate new oauth-like security policies
- provide unit-test coverage
- provide guaranties of backward compatibility to previous API versions
- solve daily problems

#### Technology & infrostructure stack

IBM WebSphere, CentOS Linux, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Elastic search, Memcached, PHP, PHP-FPM, Nginx Development & management tools & services

Jira, Confluence, Vagrant, Puppet, TeamCity, Capistrano, Composer, NewRelic, Kibana, Git, Github, Vim, PhpStorm

# Aplil 2015 - August 2015 - Badoo LTD (Senior developer, member of billing development team)

#### Goals & achievements

- Migrate some payment system integration's from oldstyle PHP4 code to modern ones
- Solving daily problems

#### Technology & infrostructure stack

 $\dots$  (NDA-protected Virtualization level)  $\dots$  Linux, Mysql, Memcached, CPQ (Cross-Platform-Queue): NDA-protected prortietary Mysql-based queue, C/C++ daemons, RRD, PHP, PHP-FPM, Nginx

#### Development & management tools & services

Jira, Confluence, google infrostructure, TeamCity, Splunk, self-written tools, Git, Subversion (they really use both), Vim, PhpStorm

#### August 2013 - March 2015 - LLC GENES1S INTELLECTUAL SOLUTIONS (Lead developer)

#### Goals & achievements

- Development management of closed indoor ERP system for binary options and bets companies.
- Management group up to 5 developers
- Dealing with designers
- Participation in negotiations with clients to introduce products and discuss technical issues

## Technology & infrostructure stack

Linux, Mysql, Redis, Memcached, Python (with NumPy/SciPy & Pandas), PHP, PHP-FPM, Apache/Nginx (I've made the migration), Javascript, ExtJs, JQuery (I've made the migration from ExtJs)

#### Development & management tools & services

RedMine, Subversion/Git (I've made the migration), Vim, PhpStorm

# May 2013 - June 2013 - Bradbury Lab LTD (Engineer/developer)

## Goals & achievements

Development of server-side video stream management application

## Technology & infrostructure stack

Linux, MongoDB, Memcached, Python, Akashi (Django-based frameworke), UWSGI, Nginx

## Development & management tools & services

Issue tracker (I don't remember was is Jira or Redmine, but deffinitely one of them), VCS (I'm really don't remember what it was), Salt, Vim, PyCharm

# August 2012 - May 2013 - Probusiness bank JSC (Web developer)

#### Goals & achievements

Developing backend web applications:

- http://yourcredithistory.ru
- http://smartmarket.net

#### Technology & infrostructure stack

Debian Linux, PostgreSQL, Memcached, Python, Django, Gevent, Flask, UWSGI, Nginx

## Development & management tools & services

Jira, Confluence, Git, PyCharm, Vim, NumPySciPy & Pandas (for analytical models experiments, was not used in production)

# March 2012 - July 2012 - 101XP (Social game porting engineer)

#### Role

I used to localize apps, that has been bought from foreign developers and integrate it with social networks.

## Goals & achievements

- Zombie Lane porting social game from Facebook (http://www.facebook.com) to Hyves (http://www.hyves.nl)
- Wasteland Empires portingsocial game from Facebook (http://www.facebook.com) to Vkontakte (http://www.vk.com) and Odnoklassinki (http://www.odnoklassniki.ru)

#### Technology & infrostructure stack

Debian Linux, Mysql, Memcached, Java, Tomcat, CoachDB, Redis, Python, Tornado, ActionScript

## Development & management tools & services

Redmine, google infrostucture, Subversion, Eclipse

# February 2011 - February 2012 - Game-Insight LLC (Junior programmer, programmer, fullstack developer)

## Projects

- Funzay high load social network, container for flash games
  - $\circ$  developing some services
  - HTML markup
- Game-insight official company's site
  - o core developing
  - o developing services

## Technology & infrostructure stack

Gentoo Linux, PostgreSQL, Memcached, PHP, PHP-FPM, Nginx, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Android Development & management tools & services

Jira, Subvrsion, Git (for Android repositories only), Eclipse, PhpStorm

## March 2009 - November 2010 - Euroinvest LLC (Programmer of IT-department)

## Goals & achievements

- developing extensions for MetaStock
- creating models for trading strategies

## Technology & infrostructure stack

Windows Server 2008, Microsoft SQL Server, C/C++, STL, Boost

## Development & management tools & services

Visual Studio

#### Core skills

- Knowledge of OOP programming paradigms like SOLID
- Knowledge of main design patterns like Singletone, Abstract Factory, Dependency Injection and so on
- Practicing extreme programming development methodology, for instance TDD or BDD patterns
- $\bullet\,$  Knowledge of main software development workflows like Agile, Kanban

# **Management Basics**

• Jira • Redmine

# Programming abilities

- Python 2.x / 3.x
  - o asyncio
  - o Django
  - $\circ$  Tornado
  - o Twisted
  - o Flask
  - Gevent
  - o SciPy/NumPy/scikit-learn
  - o Pandas
  - $\circ$  unittest/unittest2
- GO Lang
- ShellScript/Bash
- Memcached
- Redis

- PHP 4/5.x/7.x
  - o Silex
  - o Symfony 2/3/4/5
  - o Yii
  - o CakePHP
  - o Composer
  - o XDebug
  - o PHPUnit
- Queues
  - $\circ$  ZeroMQ
  - $\circ$  RabbitMQ

- SQL DBMS
  - MySQL
  - PostgreSQL
  - SQLite
  - H2
- NOSQL
  - o MongoDB
  - o Cassandra
  - o CoachDB
  - $\circ$  Reddis
  - Elastic Vertica
  - o ClickHouse

## Other abilities

- ability to use git, mercurial or subversion version control systems
- strong experience of usage Docker, Docker Compose, k8s and Helm
- experience of usage TeamCity, Jenkins, Travis and Github Actions CI
- $\bullet$  ability to impose in **LaTeX**
- fluent english
- several skills in Java (Maven, Spring 4, GWT/Ext GWT, JUnit)
- ullet several skills in **Android** development
- several skills in Javascript (JQuery, Lodash, React, Redux, Backbone, Bootstrap, ExtJs)
- several skills in C/C++ (CMake, gtest, boost/test, boost/asio) development and linux administration

## **Contact information**

Email
Phone
Skype
GitHub
Dockerhub
City

 $\begin{array}{c} {\rm g.sokol99@g\text{-}sokol.info} \\ +358\ 40\ 626\ 0274 \\ {\rm g\_a\_sokolik} \\ {\rm GSokol} \\ {\rm gsokol} \\ {\rm Helsinki} \end{array}$